Guide to the Fredericka Martin Papers ALBA.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: General Correspondence, 1937-1985
  - Giner, Consuelo (Frank Ayers' sister-in-law), 1978, 1981-1983 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Jackson, Gabriel, 1976-1979 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Jacobs, Douglas, 1939-1940, 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Keen, Judith, undated, 1975-1983 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Loeb, James, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Matthews, Herbert L., 1971-1977 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Medem, Gina, undated, 1970-1980 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Miller, Benjamin and Judith, undated, 1937, 1972-1982 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Miller, Louis, 1923, 1936-1937, 1968-1975 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Miner, Donald, 1928 (Box Shared Tamiment 209, Folder 7)
  - Moser, Dorothy, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 14A)
  - North, Joseph and Helen, undated, 1966-1976 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Nunez, Manuel, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Oram, Harold L., 1940, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Parra, Louis to Deirdre Briggs, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Patai, Frances, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 18A)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs)(incoming and outgoing, various correspondents; with performance programs, clippings, and photo of Reger), undated, 1948-1963; 1973 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs): Poetry and Essays, undated, 1935, 1940s, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 19A)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs), from Edmund Wilson, Jun 4, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Reger, Muriel (Briggs), from Lester Epstein, 1952-1953, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Reissig, Herman F., undated, 1970-1974 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Reker, Mary Lou, undated, 1979-1984 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Robbin, Violet, 1970-1972 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Rosenbaum, I. J., 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 24A)
  - Rosenstone, Robert, 1967-1972 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Sanchez Hernandez, Nestor, 1975-1984 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Segal, Benjamin, 1956-1982 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Sherman, John, undated, 1937-1940, 1971-1980 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Simon, Ruth, undated, 1969-1983 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Solovy, Jonathan, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Southworth, Herbert K., 1971 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Tobach, Charles, 1969-1976 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Weisberg, Blanche, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Wyden, Peter, undated, 1981-1984 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), undated, 1965-1966 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), 1967 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), 1968-1970 (Box 21, Folder 36A)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from Cuba), 1971 (Box 21, Folder 36B)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (from FM), 1966-1967 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Zell, Rosa Hilda (to Cedric Belfrage), undated, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 37A)
  - General Correspondence: Incoming, undated, 1967-1986 (Box 21, Folder 37B)
  - General Correspondence: Incoming (unidentified fragments), undated, 1982, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - General Correspondence: Outgoing, undated, 1965-1986 (Box 21, Folder 38A)
  - General Correspondence: Outgoing (drafts and fragments), undated, 1980-1987 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Address Book (Large) I., Undated (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Address Book (Large) II., Undated (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Address Books (Small, 4) and Business Cards, Undated (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Addresses for Emergencies (List), Undated (Box 21, Folder 43)
- Series V: General Subject Files, 1937-1990
  Series V. General Subject Files, 1937-1987. This series consists of primary and secondary materials collected by Martin in the course of her research. Notable are correspondence, leaflets and brochures related to Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee; correspondence to Martin from German volunteers held at Gurs Concentration Camp; correspondence and articles related to Jewish participation in the Spanish Civil War; clippings and notes related to aid to refugees and exiles; primary materials from the American Relief Ship for Spain and the American Rescue Ship Mission, including a donation booklet; and bibliographic sources on the Spanish Civil War.
  General materials on veterans and VALB are located in this series. The VALB files span the late 1940s through the 1980s. Particularly noteworthy are questionnaires sent by Martin and filled out by 36 veterans who were treated for wounds in Spain; memos, reports and clippings related to VALB and the Subversive Activities Control Board; programs and materials from VALB's 40th anniversary event honoring women; and notes and statements clarifying the relationship between VALB and Medical Bureau personnel.
  Much of this series is given over to the copious research notes Martin took at various repositories, chiefly at the New York Public Library and Columbia University. Martin obtained thousands of pages of photocopies from Columbia University's Spanish Refugee and Relief Organization (SRRO) collection in her efforts to document the administrative history of the Medical Bureau. [Note: These photocopies have been retained, however permission to publish these photocopied materials must be obtained in writing from Columbia University's Librarian for Rare Books and Manuscripts].
  The correspondence between Martin and Brandeis University archivist Victor Berch, who provided extensive research assistance to Martin, is a useful source of information on the course of her work, and on the establishment of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives at Brandeis. This series also includes many files of articles Martin clipped from the Cuernavaca papers (chiefly in Spanish with some English), mostly on politics and culture in Spain during the 1970s and 1980s.
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA), undated, 1974, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Alaska: Spanish Expedition to: Research Notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Allen, Jay, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - American Friends of Spanish Democracy (includes some American Medical Bureau material), undated, 1937-1938 (Box 22, Folder 3A)
  - Asociacion de Avidadores de la Republica, 1979-1984 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Associazione Italiana Combattenti Volontari Antifascisti de Spagna, 1972, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: "Los Agechados" (Comic Book Basque), 1974 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: Clippings, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: Clippings, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Basque Nationalist Movement: Clippings, 1972-1985 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Benefica Hispana, 1962-1970 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Bogin, Magda: Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1982 (Box 22, Folder 10a)
  - Book Project Contributions, undated, 1968-1978 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - British Volunteers, undated, 1938-1970 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - British Volunteers: Repatriation of Wounded, 1938-1941 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Volunteers: MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, undated, 1969-1979, 1984-1986 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Canadian Volunteers: MacKenzie-Papineau Drama (Toronto Workshop Productions), 1980-1981 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Cannon, Walter, 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Catalan Leaflets and Correspondence, ca.1970, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Catalan Protest Song, undated (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Catalonia: Clippings, 1974-1982 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Catalunya: Comissariat de Propaganda Bulletins and Leaflets, undated, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Catholic Digest: Pro-Nationaist Articles, May 1939-Mar 1940 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Centro Republicano Español, undated, 1980-1983 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - City College Volunteers-in-Spain Memorial Scholarship, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Clara Barton National Historic Site - Printed Matter, 1965-1967 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Cocteau, Jean, A Letter to Americans (pamphlet), undated (Box 22, Folder 24a)
  - Comite de Ayuda A Los Presos AntiFranquistas, undated, 1974-1976 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Committee for a Democratic Spain, undated, 1968-1970 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Communist Party of the United States: Clippings, undated, 1963-1983 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Coordinado Catalan d'Associacions d'Ex Combatents de la Republica, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Cuban Volunteers, undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Czechoslovakia: Politics: Clippings, 1968-1977 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Daily Worker: Notes on Spanish Civil War and Aid to Spain, undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - Eby, Cecil: Between the Bullet and the Lie, undated, 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - Fascism: Clippings, 1971-1982 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Film: "The Good Fight", 1980-1985 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Finnish Volunteers, undated, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Franco: Clippings, 1955-1983 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Franco: Death: Clippings, undated, 1964-1979 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Franco: Jewish Relations, undated, 1937-1939 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - French Volunteers: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1964-1981 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, undated, 1937-1939 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - German Volunteers, undated, 1963-1981 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - German Volunteers: Gurs Concentration Camp: Correspondence and Notes, 1939-1940, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Germany: Brandt, Willy, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Hungarian Volunteers: Rakoszi Battalion, undated, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - Hungary: Politics and Culture: Clippings, 1966-1981 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Ibarruri, Dolores (La Pasionaria): Clippings and Printed Matter, undated, 1970-1979 (Box 22, Folder 46)
  - International Brigades: Anniversaries, 1983, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 47)
  - International Brigades: Clippings, 1937, 1946, 1976-1983 (Box 22, Folder 48)
  - International Brigades: 40th Anniversary (Florence, Italy), undated, 1976, 1981-1984 (Box 22, Folder 49)
  - International Brigades: 50th Anniversary, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 50)
  - International Brigades: Notes and Research Materials, undated, 1937-1939, 1965-1980 (Box 22, Folder 51)
  - International Conference on the Spanish Civil War, undated, 1978-1979 (Box 22, Folder 52)
  - International Labor Defense: Aid to Spain, undated, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 53)
  - Irish: Pro-Franco Irish Christian Front, 1936, 1984? (Box 22, Folder 54)
  - Irish Volunteers, undated, 1976, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 55)
  - Israel: Commemarative Grove Honoring International Brigade Volunteers, 1972, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 56)
  - Italian Veterans: Agencia de Prensar España Popular, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 57)
  - Italy: Longo, Luigi, 1964-1980 (Box 22, Folder 58)
  - Jewish Participation in Spanish Civil War: General, undated, 1938, 1971-1985 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Participation in Spanish Civil War: Centner, Israel, undated, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Diamant, David: Correspondence, undated, 1973-1981 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Israel Veterans, undated, 1938, 1970-1986 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Medem, Gina, undated, 1937-1939, 1971-1977 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Polish, undated, 1939, 1948-1978 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Jewish Participation in the Spanish Civil War: Skorupinski, Misha: Correspondence, undated, 1972-1982 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Participation in Spanish Civil War: Toch, Joseph: Correspondence, undated, 1969-1985 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: "Anna Segher and Constancia de la Mora Tell the Story of the Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee" (pamphlet), 1945 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, undated, 1945-1951, 1968-1972 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Brochures and Leaflets, undated, 1945-1953 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Hospital Varsovia, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee: Tickets for Paul Robeson Concert, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Justice: Notes on Olimpiada Popular and Aid to Spain, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Lift the Embargo Campaign, 1938-1939 (Box 23, Folder 14A)
  - Malraux, André: Clippings, undated, 1968-1979 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Marion, George (a.k.a. James Hawthorne): "The Siege of Madrid" (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Marty, Andre, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Mexican Volunteers, undated, 1968, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Mexico: Ateneo Español: Clippings, 1975-1980 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Mexico: Spanish Republican Schools, undated, 1975, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Modotti, Tina, undated, 1975-1983 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - New Leader: Notes, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1936-1937 (Box 23, Folder 22A)
  - O'Brien, Mary Wallner: Reminiscence of Constancia de la mora (typescript), undated (Box 23, Folder 22B)
  - Photographs: Notes on Identifications, Reproduction of, etc., undated; 1937; 1968-1971; 1976 (Box 22, Folder 22a)
  - Poland: Clippings, 1970-1977 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Publishers Contacted, 1977-1978 (Box 23, Folder 23A)
  - Refugees: American Rescue Ship Mission: Leaflets, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Refugees: American Relief Ship for Spain: Correspondence, Donation Booklet, Photocopied Reports and Newsletters, undated, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Refugees: American Friends Service Committee, undated, 1950, 1975-1977 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Refugees: Aub, Max, undated, 1972, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Refugees: Bosch: Gimpera, Pedro, 1974, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Refugees: Buñuel, Luis: Clippings, 1973-1983 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Refugees: Casals, Pablo, 1970-1979 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Refugees: Galleani Case (Photocopies), 1939 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Refugees: German-American Relief Committee, undated, 1940 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Refugees: German Exiles in Mexico, 1974, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Refugees: Gónzales Fleischman, Ernestine, 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Refugees: de la Mora, Constancia, undated, 1940, 1964-1980 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Refugees: Neken, Margarita, 1964-1969 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Refugees: Relief and Aid, undated, 1937-1949, 1978-1979 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Refugees: Sender, Ramón, 1943, 1972-1978 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Refugees: Spanish Doctors in Mexico, undated, 1969-1979 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles, undated, 1973-1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles in France, 1939-1940, 1970-1981 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles in Mexico, undated, 1962-1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles in Mexico: Clippings, 1939, 1959-1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Refugees: Spanish Exiles Return to Spain: Clippings, 1976-1978 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Refugees: Xirgu, Margarita: Clippings, 1969-1974 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Republican Government in Exile, undated, 1960-1980 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Research: Contact Information for Medical and Combat Veterans, undated, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Research: General Notes and Queries, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves,"Outline of Chapters and Appendices and Chapter Excerpts, undated (Box 24, Folder 9A)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Outline, Title Headings, etc. (Box 24, Folder 9B)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Chapter 1, Drafts and Materials, undated, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 9C)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Chapter 2, Drafts and Materials, undated (Box 24, Folder 9D)
  - Research: Book, "Proud within Ourselves," Chapter IV, Drafts and Materials, undated (Box 24, Folder 9E)
  - Research: Interview Subjects (Lists and Notes), undated, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Research Funding: General (I), 1970-1976 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Research Funding: General (II) (Box 24, Folder 11A)
  - Research Funding: American Philosophical Society, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 11B)
  - Research Funding: Louis Rabinowitz Foundation Application, undated, 1968-1972 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 1), undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 2), undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 3), undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 4), undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 5), undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 6), 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Research Notebooks (Folder 7), 1977 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Research Questionnaire: International Brigade Veterans (Blank), undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Research Questionnaires: Medical Service Volunteers (Blank), undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Research Repository: Adelphi University, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Research Repository: Archivo General de Indias (Sevilla), undated, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Research Repository: Biblioteca Nacional and Central (Spain), 1941, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence (includes undated FM notes/comments on the archives at Brandeis), undated, Oct 1970-Apr 1971 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor, May 1971-Jul 1971 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Aug 1971-Dec 1971 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1972-Mar 1972 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Apr 1971-Sep 1972 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Oct 1972-Dec 1972 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1973-Jul 1973 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Aug 1973-Dec 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor (appointed as FM's research associate), Nov 30, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3A)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jul 1974-Dec 1974 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1974-Jun 1974 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, Jan 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor: Correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Research Repository: Brandeis: Berch, Victor (from FM, drafts and fragments), Undated (Box 25, Folder 9A)
  - Research Repository: British Medical Association Library, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 1, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 2, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 3, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 4, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 5, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Notes, Folder 6, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection: Guide and Research Correspondence, undated, 1963, 1972-1975 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), 1936 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 1, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 2, 1937 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 3, 1937 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 1, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), Folder 2, 1938 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), 1939 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Research Repository: Columbia University: Spanish Refugee Relief Organization Collection (Photocopies and Transcriptions), 1940 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Research Repository: Hispanic Society of America, undated, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Research Repository: Hermoteca Municipal (Madrid), undated, 1970-1972 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Research Repository: Hoover Library, 1964-1978 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Research Repository: Imperial War Museum, undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Research Repository: Institut d'Historia dels Moviments d'Emanciopacio National I Social (Catalan Organization, Paris), 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Research Repository: International Institute for Social History, undated, 1983-1985 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Research Repository: Library of Congress: General, undated, 1970-1977 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Research Repository: Library of Congress: Notes and Photocopies, undated, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Research Repository: MacMasters University (Hamilton, Ontario), undated, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Research Repository: McGill University, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Research Repository: National Archives and Records Service, undated, 1978-1985 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Research Repository: National Library of Medicine, undated, 1971-1978 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Research Repository: New York Academy of Medicine Library, undated, 1971, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Research Repository: New York Public Library: Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1949-1970 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Research Repository: New York Public Library: McKelvy White Collection: Notes, undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Research Repository: New York Public Library: McKelvy White Collection: Pamphlet and Serials, undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Research Repository: Northwestern University, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Research Repository: Ohio Wesleyan University, undated, 1969-1971 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Research Repository: Salamanca Archives, undated, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Research Repository: Servicio Historico Militar, undated, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Research Repository: United Nations Library, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Research Repository: U.S. Army/U.S. Air Force: Joint Medical Library, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - Research Repository: University of California at Berkeley (Bancroft Library), undated, 1966-1972 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Research Repository: University of California at San Diego, undated, 1971-1976 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Research Repository: Yale, 1977-1980 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Robeson, Paul, undated, 1979, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - "Romancero de Chichicastenango" (typescript copy with notes and introduction by the author, Rosa Hilda Zell, etc.), undated, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 31a)
  - Romania: Clippings, 1964-1982 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - Small, Charles, undated, 1970-1978 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - Soviet Union: Clippings, 1966-1975 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Soviet Union: Jews, undated, 1971-1974 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - Spain: Alfonso XIII and Victoria Eugenia: Clippings, undated, 1941-1975 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Spain: Alfonso XIII: Pamphlet, 1927 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Spain: Alveriz de Toledo, Isabel, duquesa de Medina Sidonia: Clippings, 1967-1970 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - Spain: Amnesty for Republicans: Clippings, 1976-1983 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - Spain: Anarchists: Clippings, 1972-1981 (Box 26, Folder 40)